Karthikeyan Senthil Nayagam

Mechanical Engineer

Vaughan, ON L6A 3R4 karthikeyansenthilnayagam4_wgc@indeedemail.com 6476173557

Permanent Resident looking for opportunities in Canada. Highly motivated Project Engineer with 3+ years of accomplished experience in Project Management with supervising skills to control the production floor, CAD Designing and Quality Assurance of received and finished parts with Lean Six Sigma Green Belt. Looking for opportunities as Mechanical, Design and Quality Engineer, to utilize my experience and my Canadian master's degree.

#readytowork

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Mechanical Engineer

Yenkay Industries - Chennai, Tamil Nadu January 2016 to October 2019

- · Working along with the Managing director in creating control plans and PFMEA
- Conducting APQP meetings to discuss about process and material requirements
- Creating Process mapping and process flow chart
- · Planned and implemented Engineering programs according to the customer requirements
- Provided Reports of the status of the projects and adjusting the schedules when required
- Working in CAD Software such as SOLIDWORKS, INVENTOR and AUTOCAD in generating CAD Drawing from the given sample, drawings or templates from the customer
- Maintenance Planning: Planning Schedules for Daily, Week and Monthly Maintenance Schedules for production equipment and Preventive Maintenance Planning
- Generating drawings indicating the different process involved in the part and issuing it to the shop floor
- Performed Receiving Inspection, Line Inspection and In-plant Inspection and provided reports
- Coordinated the dispatch and receiving of outsourced parts and maintaining records of them
- Inspecting outsourced parts and verifying them before sending it to the shop floor, conducted hardness test using Rockwell hardness machine
- Attended customer meetings regarding quality control and supplier standards
- 5s implementation of drawing yellow lines on the shop floor defining machine and safe path of operations
- · Conducted Audit at supplier company giving scores, feedback and areas of improvement
- 5S implementation of the office, workplace and warehouse on the basis of scores. Implementations of KAIZEN in making the production more efficient
- Providing contractors, suppliers, visitors, seasonal workers and third party service providers are provided with the written instructions such as GMP's and Confidentiality Agreement..

- Assist in the implementation of improvements on equipment and processes related to Environmental, Health and Safety and compliance to Health and Safety regulatory and company policy requirements.
- Reports, manages and documents any incidents or findings on safety of equipment, processes, employee behaviours, hazards incidents to plant management for resolution as required.

CAD Designer

Future Temp Glass - Toronto, ON August 2014 to July 2015

- Used PRO CAD and AUTO CAD for drafting glasses for several industrial and commercial application, switching between Metric and English units and designing complex shapes and notches with higher accuracy
- Used to import .dxf files from the customer and also used scanning machine to create shapes from the templates given by the customer
- CAM PROGRAMMING: with the help of PRO CAD Software used to create programs for the machining purposes mainly milling program to determine the type of cutter and adding polishing sequence and determining the start and finish of a machining process and building up stoppers
- Order Creation: Able to create orders and create bill of materials and estimate the cost of the entire process and reporting to the owner
- Able to communicate with machinist on the shop floor to address the issues and make the changes in the drawings and to address any issues in the shop floor
- · Providing WHMIS training and Health and safety Training

Education

Master of Engineering in Mechanical Engineer

University of Windsor - Windsor January 2012 to October 2013

Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Anna University - Chennai, Tamil Nadu August 2007 to May 2011

Skills

- Autodesk Inventor
- Engineer
- Drafting
- CAD
- Autodesk
- Project Management
- CNC
- Mechanical Design
- Autocad

Certifications and Licenses

Lean Six Sigma Green BeltJuly 2019 to Present